{
    "id": "ee3eaab96f0d4cdeb34160b47cc30ba0",
    "title": "Intermediate Level Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "It is …………………………… dark that I cannot see anything.",
            "description": "We use so...that... to indicate cause and effect. ",
            "answers": [
                "very",
                "too",
                "so"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "e9ee0b6d42204e939fbd7ee5866cd5bf"
        },
        {
            "question": "He is …………………………… to understand this.",
            "description": "Enough shows sufficiency. It goes after the adjective or adverb modified by it. ",
            "answers": [
                "so clever",
                "too clever",
                "clever enough"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "d6d305d3c39847b9a1b46a3a9382d5af"
        },
        {
            "question": "What a charming girl ………………………….!",
            "description": "In exclamations we do not use inversion. That means the subject goes before the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is she",
                "she is"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d60c7eabeec842cf8cdd19366c2793dd"
        },
        {
            "question": "She is ………………………… young to go to school.",
            "description": "Note the pattern too..to...",
            "answers": [
                "so",
                "very",
                "too",
                "enough"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "c4f126bfd65745c5b7d7c60ead94d638"
        },
        {
            "question": "How ………………………….. the holiday has passed!",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "quick",
                "quickly"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6f7901ed9a024a43ad924ce0610e69aa"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you hurt the dog, it …………………………….. you.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will bite",
                "bites",
                "would bite"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "56c01dbb8d1e4a16ab7005714904d1d2"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had gone to university, I …………………………… a better job.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "can find",
                "could find",
                "could have found"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "2237eaf5dd004addbebbe5336b87a5d3"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you were a billionaire, how ……………………………. you spend your time?",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past in the if-clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "can",
                "would"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "145f2fab79a34347984c59b7f0cac21b"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had left that wasp alone, it …………………………………… you.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will not sting",
                "would not sting",
                "would not have stung"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "f11213772a2f4a398b3d4d526dc81fce"
        },
        {
            "question": "It is no good ……………………………… to her.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to talk",
                "talking"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "22fd4888d80045939cf842763f63c40f"
        },
        {
            "question": "It was careless …………………………… her to make that mistake.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "with",
                "of",
                "for"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "8721fc9a8ede4964857e9d60a6e610c0"
        },
        {
            "question": "It is wicked ………………………….. him to say such things.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "of",
                "with"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "ed66a95fb18b48858091e6303d0a3788"
        }
    ]
}